<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Reviews on Kathryn Loosemore PhD</title>
    <link>/categories/book-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Reviews on Kathryn Loosemore PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/book-reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book review published in &#39;Perspectives on Terrorism&#39;, Volume XIX, Issue 2, June 2025</title>
      <link>/research/book-review-perspectives-terrorism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/book-review-perspectives-terrorism/</guid>
      <description>Dr Loosemore reviews &amp;lsquo;Javier Argomaniz, Resisting Terror: Civil Action and Non-Violent Resistance to Terrorism in Basque Country&amp;rsquo; in the June edition (iIssue 2) of &amp;lsquo;Perspectives on Terrorism&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;It has been more than seven years since the Basque militant group ETA (Euskadi Ta Askatasuna) disarmed and disbanded following a bloody campaign that lasted almost 60 years. The complexity of ETA’s campaign, and the factors that eventually brought their reign of terror in the Basque Country to an end, are the subject of Resisting Terror: Civil Action and Non-Violent Resistance to Terrorism in Basque Country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Counter-terror by proxy: the Spanish State’s illicit war with ETA</title>
      <link>/research/counter_terror_by_proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/counter_terror_by_proxy/</guid>
      <description>It has been almost 5 years since the Basque militant group ETA (Euskadi Ta Askatasuna) disarmed and disbanded following a bloody campaign that lasted almost 60 years. In Counter-terror by proxy: The Spanish State’s illicit war with ETA, Emmanuel-Pierre Guittet takes a deep dive into a specific period in the conflict (1983-1987), during which a group of state-sponsored mercenaries carried out their own brutal campaign that spanned the French-Spanish border. The group was called GAL (Grupos Antiterroristas de Liberacion) and its targets were suspected ETA members and supporters.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
